Hugo Lopez Ferrer

12911 Sunstone Ave, Orlando, Florida 32832

+1 321-343-9201 | recibecorreo@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Bachelor's Degree in Economics with a specialization in Marketing, with extensive experience in real estate consulting since 2008. Developed skills in property maintenance and remodeling, leading to the establishment of a family business in Venezuela and Chile. In the United States, worked in building maintenance, commercial spaces, and residential areas, as well as inventory optimization and event management. Currently freelancing as an Al Generalist, Data Analyst, and Strategist Reviewer for Outlier. Technical experience includes skills in various software and competencies in emerging technologies such Generative Al, Prompt Engineering (English and Spanish), Data Labeling, and Data Analysis.

Professional Experience

Outlier

Freelance - Remote | Al Generalist, Data Analyst, and Strategist Reviewer | Independent Consultant August 2024 - Present, Orlando, Florida, USA

Model training and fine-tuning: Specializing in training and fine-tuning Large Language Models (LLMs) and Machine Learning (ML) models using techniques such as Reinforcement Learning from Human Feedback (RLHF).

Prompt engineering: Creating and optimizing prompts to obtain accurate and relevant responses from language models.

Data labeling: Classifying and annotating data to effectively train and evaluate models.

Model refinement: Continuously improving models by identifying and correcting biases and errors in responses.

Model evaluation: Comprehensive analysis of the quality of model-generated responses, including their factuality and relevance, classifying and ranking Al-generated responses, ensuring consistency, relevance, and factuality.

Prompt refinement: Writing and optimizing prompts to improve the quality and coherence of language model outputs.

Fact-checking: Researching and corroborating Al-generated information to ensure accuracy.

WorldMark Orlando - Kingstown Reef

Engineering and Maintenance Contractor
March 2024 – May 2024, Orlando, Florida, USA

Implemented data entry system to reduce inventory processing time, performed preventive/corrective maintenance for smooth resort operations, maintained accurate equipment records through meticulous data entry, cultivated positive relationships with guests for a welcoming environment

Somos Manotas

Maintenance and Cleaning Operations
July 2023 – February 2024, Orlando, Florida, USA

Utilized data entry to manage inventory for maintenance tasks, provided corrective/preventive maintenance to maintain facility integrity, managed event operations for seamless execution and guest satisfaction, contributed to a clean environment through cleaning and landscaping

Century 21 Chile

Real Estate Agent

January 2019 - March 2023, Metropolitan Santiago Region, Chile

Leveraged market data and expertise to guide clients in buying, selling, and renting properties. Managed property listings and fostered trusting client relationships through effective communication. Handled all aspects of tenant management, including applications, leases, rent collection, property records, maintenance coordination, and communication.

RENT A HOUSE

Real Estate Advisor

March 2008 - November 2018, Zulia, Venezuela

Real estate advisor in the purchase, sale and rental of apartments, houses, commercial premises, warehouses, plots, offices and everything related in the business. Utilized property management software (FlexMLS) to streamline tenant management tasks.

Education

La Universidad Del Zulia, Maracaibo, Zulia, Venezuela *Bachelor's Degree in Economics, Marketing Specialization* 1990 – 1995

La Universidad Del Zulia, Maracaibo, Zulia, Venezuela Avanced Diploma Neuro-Linguistic Programming Coach (NLP Coach) Jan/May 2016

Skills

- Inventory Management: Expertise in HOTSoS and inventory control systems.
- Data Entry: Precision and efficiency with Microsoft 365, Google Sheets, Docs, and Forms.
- Preventive & Corrective Maintenance: Extensive experience in diagnosing and repairing equipment.
- Customer Relationship Management (CRM): Effective communication and exceptional customer service.
- Engineering Control: Strong understanding of engineering principles and CMMS.
- Event Operations Management: Planning, organizing, and executing successful events.
- Al and Data Technologies: Competencies in algorithms, neural networks, machine learning, computer vision, and natural language processing.
- IT Technical Troubleshooting & Systems Proficiency: Proficient in fundamental technical troubleshooting, encompassing networking hardware/software and core concepts of computer architecture, binary code, and Linux OS.

Last Courses:

- Amazon Q introduction (AWS): Generative AI, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Amazon Q
- Python for Data Science, AI & Development (IBM): Data Science, Data Analysis, Python Programming Basics, NumPy Basics, Pandas Basics, Jupyter Notebooks, Beautiful Soup Basics.

- **Technical Support Fundamentals** (Google): Binary Code, Customer Support, Linux Basics, Troubleshooting, Communication, Networking Hardware, Computer Networking, Computer Architecture
- Building AI Powered Chatbots Without Programming (IBM): IBM Watson, Conversational Chatbot, Watson Assistant, WordPress, Deploy Chatbots, Cloud Computing, Computer Programming, IBM Cloud, MachineLearning.
- Chatbot Building Essentials (Coursera): AI, Watson Assistant, Chatbots, PWID-B0066100
- **Generative AI: Prompt Engineering** (Coursera): Generative AI, LLMs, Prompt Engineering, Machine Learning, Applied Machine Learning, Prompt Engineering Approaches, Prompt Patterns, Artificial Neural Networks.
- Introduction to Artificial Intelligence (AI) (IBM): Applied Machine Learning, Artificial Neural Networks, Algorithms, Computer Vision, Deep learning, Human Learning, Machine Learning, Prompt Engineering, Algorithm, NLP.
- Introduction to Generative AI (Google): Prompt Engineering, Google Cloud, Generative AI Studio, Generative AI Google Tools, Generative AI Google Apps.
- Introduction to Generative AI Learning Path Specialization (Google): LLMs, Generative AI, Ethical and Responsible AI, Data Management, AI Principles with Google Cloud, LLMs Foundations, LLMs Aplications.
- Introduction to Large Language Models (Google): Prompt Engineering, LLMs, LLMs Aplications, LLMs Performance, Gen Ai Google Apps, LLMs Fields.
- Introduction to Responsible AI (Google): AI Principles with Google Cloud, AI Responsible, AI Ethicals, AI Google 7 Principles.
- Responsible AI: Applying AI Principles with Google Cloud (Google): AI Principles with Google Cloud, Ethical and Responsible AI, AI Google 7 Principles, Machine Learning, Deep learning.
- **Project Initiation: How to start a successful project** (Google): Leadership and Management, Planning, Project Management, Adaptability, Organizational Development, Change Management, Decision Making.
- Foundations of Project Management (Google): Project Management, Strategy and Operations, Business Communications, Change Management, Organizational Development.

See the courses and more at:

https://www.coursera.org/learner/hugo-lopez

www.linkedin.com/in/hugolopezferrer

https://www.credly.com/users/hugo-lopez.55394a1c